Artnet built a custom image model on Google Cloud platform using TensorFlow,
アートネットはTensorFlowを使って カスタム画像モデルを構築しました
there on the left-hand side of this image.
画像の左側にありますね
But increasingly, you don't have to do that.
しかし だんだんその必要も なくなってきました
There are a variety of domains where Google
Googleではトレーニング済みの
exposes Machine Learning Services train but our own data.
機械学習サービスを多数公開しています
For example, if you want to transcribe speech,
たとえば 会話の文字起こしをする際
you could use a speech API instead of having to collect audio data,
Speech APIを使えば音声データの収集
train it, and predict with it.
トレーニングや予測は必要ありません
There are many such pre-train models.
このようなトレーニング済みのモデルが たくさんあります
And such pre-train models are excellent ways to replace user input by machine learning.
トレーニング済みモデルは ユーザー入力を 機械学習で置き換える優れた方法です
Here's an example of using a pre-train model.
トレーニング済みモデルの例を紹介します
Ocado is a world's largest online only grocery.
オカドは世界最大級のネットスーパーです
It's based in the UK.
イギリスの会社です
And the way it used to work,
以前は
was a customer sended email.
顧客がメールで発注していました
And traditionally, each email would get
メールは読まれてから
read and then routed to the appropriate E-department,
担当部署に送られ
where it would get read again.
また読まれます
So that doesn't scale.
スケーラビリティがありませんね
So, Ocado turned to natural language processing.
そこで オカドは 自然言語処理を利用しました
And they were able to extract the sentiment of the email and entities,
メールから感情や内容を抽出し
the things being talked about in the email,
何について書かれているか
and even the syntax of the email.
構文まで認識できるようになりました
And this computational technology helps Ocado parse through the body of emails and
この技術によってオカドは メールの内容を解析し
tag and route these e-mails to help
タグ付けして 担当者に送り
the contact center reps determine the priority and context in a very efficient way.
優先度や内容を効率的に 把握できるようになりました
But increasingly, customers do not want to go to your website and click on a button.
しかし近年 顧客はウェブサイトに アクセスしなくなっています
They do not want to send you an email.
メールを送ることも嫌がります
They want to talk to you, interactively.
直接話したいのです
To get their questions and concerns answered.
欲しい情報をすぐに得たいというわけです
Manually, answering each call doesn't scale,
人間が電話応対していては スケーラビリティがありません
and so Gartner estimates that in a few years,
ガートナーによると数年のうちに
we will be spending more on conversational interfaces that even on mobile apps.
対話型インターフェースの利用が モバイルアプリでも増えるとのことです
So does this mean using the speech API,
この場合 Speech APIを使って
transcribing the speech, and then trying to make sense of it?
会話を文字に起こして認識するのでしょうか
No. What I'm showing you here is
そうではありません
a high-level conversational agent tool called Dialogflow.
Dialogflowという高度な 対話型エージェントツールを使います
So look here at this screen and we notice that the agent says,
画面上のエージェントに注目してください
"How may I help you today?"
「いらっしゃいませ」と言います
And the customer says,
顧客がこう答えます
"I want to get a pizza with bacon and cheese."
「ベーコンとチーズのピザを1つ」
And based on that,
それに反応し
Dialogflow goes ahead and builds
Dialogflowは
a JSON message that says that the customer wants to order a pizza,
ピザ注文という趣旨の JSONメッセージを作成し
and is able to go ahead and add the toppings corresponding to bacon and cheese.
ベーコンとチーズのトッピングを追加します
And then the agent says,
次にエージェントは
"Well, what size do you want?"
「サイズは何にしますか？」と聞きます
Because that's another requirement and based on that,
必須事項の1つです
the size as large also gets added and the standard crust and then says, "Oh add olives."
Lサイズと標準クラストが追加され 「オリーブも追加」と言われます
And now, into the toppings, olives gets added.
今度はトッピングにオリーブが追加されます
Notice that is a very conversational interface and from these conversations,
高度な対話型のインターフェースの会話から
a JSON structured message gets built and it's this JSON message,
JSON形式のメッセージが 作成されていきます
this very structured message that goes to
この非常に構造化されたメッセージが
the rest of the application which works the same way as before,
従来と同じ働きをするアプリに 入力されますが
except that the user input has not come from the customer pointing
ユーザー入力は
instead has come through a conversational interface.
対話型インターフェースによって行われました